准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fis
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
珍珍过生日
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
爱哭男孩
早安  裤头村
Good morning, Bikini Bottom
今天可是个特别的日子
It is a very special day today
因为我们要播出爱哭男孩的全新单曲
because we've got the new single from boys who cry
你就是主角
It's all about you
你就是女主角
It's all about you, girl
庆祝你十六岁生日
On your 16th birthday
我们目光向你看齐
We'll pay attention to you, girl
大家对你言听计从
Everyone has to do just what you say
今晚全场灯光聚焦于你
You'll get your very own spotlight tonight
因为你就是主角
'Cause it's all about you
也就是珍珍
Yeah, it's all about Pearl
珍珍
你就是寿星
You're the birthday girl
对  我就是主角
Yeah, it's all about me
珍珍
Yeah, Pearl
庆祝我十六岁生日
On my 16th birthday
我要音乐跟衣服  还有亮晶晶的东西
I want music and clothes and shiny things
快快掌声鼓励
So give it up right away
全世界的大众
Everybody in the whole wide world
目光向我看齐
they have to pay attention to me
主角就是我  我
It's all about me, me
再猜猜是谁
And guess who
我
Me
搞什么鬼
Neptune's trousers
早安  老爸
Morning, daddy
你确定不要睡一楼吗
Are you sure you wouldn't
prefer a room on the ground floor?
老爸
Daddy
只是兴奋嘛  因为明天可是特别日子
I'm just excited because tomorrow's a very special day
是吗
It is?
我是说  确实
I mean, it is
很特别
Very special
的确非常非常特别
Very, very special indeed
你不知道明天是什么日子吧
You have no idea what day tomorrow is, do you?
完全不知道
None at all
明天是我十六岁生日
It's my 16th birthday
我早知道了
I knew that
你怎么会以为我不知道呢
How could you think I wouldn't know that?
长到几岁  十二吗
What are you going to be, 12?
我要十六岁了
I'm going to be 16
这可是我一生唯一最重要的生日
It's only the most important birthday in my entire life
我要是没有棒得不得了的派对
If I don't have a completely awesome party
就会在整个高中生涯都抬不起头来
my whole high school reputation will collapse
只能被迫辍学
I'll have to drop out
没法上大学
I won't go off to college
出不了家门一步
I'll never leave home
我后半辈子都得让你来养
You'll have to support me for the rest of my life
那种事情绝对不能发生
Well, we don't want that to happen
那就保证今年给我办个真正的派对
Then promise me you'll give me a real party this year
不许小气
And don't be cheap
高中
嗨  姐妹们
Hi, girls
嗨  珍珍
Hi, Pearl
你们要不要
Are you guys coming
明天来参加我的生日炫派对啊
to my totally coral birthday party tomorrow?
不好吧  珍珍
I don't know, Pearl
这次派对会不会跟去年一样炫啊
Is this going to be as totally coral as last year
那时你爸还发回形针当派对礼物呢
when your dad passed out paper clips as party favors?
记得那回咱都只能共用一个气球呢
Remember the time we all had to share one balloon?
得了吧
Please
记得骑小马不
Remember the pony ride?
等不及要看他今年怎么个搞砸法了
I can't wait to see how he ruins this year
蟹堡王
老爸
Daddy
全体做好防撞姿势
Everybody, brace for impact
快说你给我生日派对准备了炫东西
Tell me you've got something totally coral
planned for my birthday party
你别急嘛
Now, now, don't snap your mizzenmast
全都准备好了
Everything is all set
我都已经买好派对礼物了
Why, I've already got the party favors
泡泡包装膜
Bubble wrap
今年一定会特别劲爆
This year's gonna be a blast
老爸  你搞砸了我先前所有生日派对
Daddy, you ruined all my birthday parties
最好别给我把这次也搞砸了
But you better not ruin this one
答应我  不要小气
Now, promise me you won't be cheap
我答应
I promise
好
Good
因为我列了张清单
Because I made a list
正在驶出裤头村
清单上的东西都得在派对上配齐了
Now, I want everything on this list at my party
再见
Bye
我跟我朋友去逛商场了
I'll be at the mall with my friends
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
怎么了  蟹老板
Yes, Mr. Krabs?
我布置派对
While I plan the party
就由你负责去买珍珍的礼物
I want you to buy Pearl's present
拿去  小子
Here you go, boy
这是什么  蟹老板
What's this, Mr. Krabs?
是我的信用卡
It's me credit card
可以拿它当钱用
You use it instead of money
用这个塑料片就可以买东西吗
I can buy stuff with just this piece of plastic?
用不着钱吗
I don't need money?
没错
Exactly
别忘了  什么都配不上我的小珍珍
Now remember, nothing's too good for me little Pearl
我虽然本来想什么都不给她
I wanted to give her nothing
可是她不应该什么都不配
But she's too good for that
快跟踪她  看她喜欢什么
Now follow her around and see what she likes
也就是去干包打听
You know, do some detective work
包打听
Detective work
我要卧底了
I'm going undercover
裤头村商场
那时候玛西跟我说
So that's when Marcie told me
商场
茱莉说安吉拉她确实喜欢布拉德
that Julie said that Angela did like Brad
安吉拉喜欢布拉德
Angela likes Brad
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
这就是我见过世上最棒的东西了
This is the greatest thing
I have seen in the whole world
收银
我要用这片塑料买那块塑料
I'd like to buy that piece of plastic
with this piece of plastic
鲤事达
尤金蟹先生
蟹老板是吗
Mr. Krabs, huh?
快说
Quick
蟹这个字怎么写
How do you spell "Krabs"?
里面肯定有个虫
I'm pretty sure it has a "b" in it
差不多
Close enough
拿去吧  小子
Here you go, kid
就这样吗
That's it?
我永远不懂高级金融是如何运作的
I'll never understand the workings of high finance
这就是我全世界见过最棒的东西了
This is the greatest thing
I've ever seen in the whole world
闪光唇彩
Glitter gloss
不会吧
Oh, no
我买错礼物了
I bought the wrong present
珍珍  一定要来看看这个
Pearl, you have got to see this
来了  朱迪
Coming, Judy
这个一看就是最棒的礼物
Now, this is obviously the greatest present ever
美妆
这就是全世界最棒的东西了
This is the greatest thing in the whole world
横幅挂好了  蟹老板
The banner's up, Mr. Krabs
她出生那天我就买了那横幅
I've had that since the day she was born
特地趁着特价买的
I got it on sale
喜得贵子
女
×
她一定会喜欢的  蟹老板
I'm sure she'll love it, Mr. Krabs
宠物
这匹小海马最可爱了
This sea pony is the cutest thing ever
想不想回家当我的小马驹呢
Do you want to come home and be my pony?
珍珍  过来
Pearl, come here
这个可炫了
This is so coral
狗鱼                   小海马
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
是比利鱼金
It's Billy fishkin
嗨  比利
Hi, Billy
他好俊啊
Isn't he dreamy?
促销
四号收银台需要确认价格
Price check on four
珍珍的塑像做好了  蟹老板
I finished Pearl's portrait, Mr. Krabs
好一个旷世巨作
It's a true masterpiece
早知道就雇佣先前那个冰雕师傅了
Maybe I should have hired that ice sculptor
什么冰雕师傅
Ice sculptor?
冰雕连傻子都会
Any fool can sculpt in ice
只有真正的天才
It takes true genius
能做到把四百磅蟹黄堡生肉饼
to transform 400 pounds of raw krabby patties
塑造成此般的巨作
into a work of such majesty
好
Yeah
装饰算是办妥了
Well, we've got the decor covered
娱乐又是怎么个事
Now, how about entertainment?
我看看啊
Let me see here
珍珍想要个叫做爱哭男孩的男团
Pearl wants some boy band called boys who cry
爱哭男孩吗
Boys who cry?
他们可是我最爱的男团
They're my favorite band
出场费可是要一百万啊
They charge a million dollars just to show up
要他们假唱得花大钱的
If you want them to lip-sync, it'll run into real money
你是真爱粉吧
You're a real fan, huh?
没错
Oh, yeah
他们的歌我都懂一点
I know all their songs
他们的歌你都懂吗
All their songs?
墨镜
鞋               贵帽
垃圾
我爸给我这个当生日礼物一定会很酷
Wouldn't it be cool if my dad got me this for my birthday?
确实  前提是他得先酷再说
It sure would be, if he was cool
可惜他不酷
Which he's not
对啊  他可能又要给我送一盒订书钉
Yeah, he probably got me another box of staples
派对就快要开始了
It's almost time for the party to start
我回来了  蟹老板
I'm back, Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝  干什么耗这么久
SpongeBob, what took you so long?
珍珍的礼物呢
And where's Pearl's present?
送快递的车马上就来
The delivery truck will be here momentarily
她来了  蟹老板
Here she comes, Mr. Krabs
全体就位
Everybody get in position
生日快乐
Happy birthday
喜得贵子
女
×
喜得贵子
"It's a boy"?
老爸
Daddy
爆米花
爆米花都馊了
Stale popcorn
味道像刷锅水
It tastes like dishwater
本来就是刷锅水
It is dishwater
那玩意是我吗
Is that supposed to be me?
用蟹黄堡肉饼做的
It's made out of krabby patties
恶心
Gross
谁要吃蛋糕啊
Who wants cake?
蛋糕看着挺好吃
Well, the cake does look good
这蛋糕用纸板做的
It's made out of cardboard
加了糖霜哦
And frosting
珍珍
Pearl
你派对连土16次了
16 lame parties in a row
想必是破纪录了
Must be a new record
我们还是走吧
Let's get out of here
等等
Wait
别走
Don't leave
我爸请了爱哭男孩来演出
My dad got boys who cry to play
你请到了爱哭男孩对吧
You did get boys who cry, right?
比那更好呢  宝贝
Even better, sweetie
开始
Hit it
小姐们好
Hello, ladies
每当我泪水流个不停
When my tear ducts give issue
不能用随便什么纸巾
I can't use just any tissue
必须要四层
I need four-ply
四层
Four-ply
才哭得动
When I cry
那就不是爱哭男孩
That is not boys who cry
对
Yeah
烂
Boo
太劣质了
What a rip-off
好个垃圾
This stinks
老爸  你怎么能这样
Daddy, how could you?
我都给你清单了
I gave you a list
珍珍  回来啊
Pearl, come back
又是全都让你给搞砸了
You ruined everything
干什么都小气  就连对我都小气
You couldn't stop being cheap, even for me
我会想办法补偿你的  珍珍
I'll make it up to you somehow, Pearl
可以了
That's it
倒过来
Back it up
倒到这来
Right there
倒下来
Let 'er go
你给我买了艘船吗
You bought me a boat?
有吗
I did?
我是说
I mean
真有吗
I did?
老爸  不知道一切还能再好到哪去
Daddy, I don't know how it could get better than this
看好了
Just watch
大家开始吧
Hit it, boys
你就是女主角
It's all about you, girl
庆祝你十六岁生日
On your 16th birthday
我们目光向你看齐
We'll pay attention to you, girl
大家对你言听计从
Everyone has to do just what you say
今晚全场灯光聚焦于你
You'll get your very own spotlight tonight
因为你就是主角
'Cause it's all about you
也就是珍珍
Yeah, it's all about Pearl
你就是寿星
You're the birthday girl
小子
Boy
这些花了我多少钱
How much is all this costing me?
这是收据
Here's the receipt
我非得
I ought to--
老爸
Daddy
你给了我想要的一切
You got me everything I wanted
什么都配不上我的小珍珍
Nothing's too good for me daughter
你真是个好爸爸  蟹老板
You're a good dad, Mr. Krabs
别得寸进尺  小子
Don't push your luck, boy
空手道岛
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
客串
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
好了  小蜗
Okay, Gary
准备好来做一年一次的背壳打蜡没
ready for your yearly shell waxing?
壳蜡
看看这光芒
Just look at that shine
来进壳里看一看吧
Now let's check under the hood
天啊  小蜗
Geez, Gary
这地方脏得跟蜗牛圈似的
this place is a real snail-sty
一直没清
Still?
跨年夜就这样了
From New Year's Eve?
什么
What?
我一直都在到处找这个呢  小蜗
I've been looking everywhere for this, Gary
我最爱的新奇搞怪T恤
My favorite novelty t-shirt
有人来了
Someone's here
给海绵宝宝的特别快递
Special delivery for SpongeBob SquarePants
特别快递
Special delivery?
给我的吗
Just for me?
你觉得我很
You think I'm
特别吗
special?
行了
Alright
每次给你送快递都非得遭这种罪吗
do we have to go through this
every time I give you your mail?
今天会是什么呢  小蜗
What could it be today, Gary?
一个录像带
A videotape?
你是大赢家
"You're a winner --
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants"
我就是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob SquarePants
空手道岛
Karate Island
一个充满自然与美景的宁静异域之地
A serene and exotic location
where nature and beauty abound
几百般武艺在此碰撞
and hundreds of fighting styles collide
并且永不停息  紧张刺激
in a wave of non-stop, pulsating
无拘无束地行动着
no-hold barred action
行动
几个世纪以来
For centuries
世界顶尖空手道大师
the world's top karate artists
来到这片热土
have journeyed to this land
加冕成为空手道之王
to be crowned King of Karate
空手道
空手道之王
King of Karate?
现在到你了
Now it's your turn
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
你赢得了
You've won
前往空手道岛的全额免费旅行
an all-expense paid trip to Karate Island
空手道岛
你将在此加冕为今年的空手道之王
Where you'll be crowned this year's King of Karate
空手道之王
听到了吗  小蜗
Did you hear that, Gary?
我要被加冕为
I'm gonna be crowned
空手道之王
King of Karate
你好  海绵宝宝
Howdy, SpongeBob
你好  珊迪
Hello, Sandy
你听说了没
Have you heard the news?
我要受邀去空手道岛
I've been invited to Karate Island
加冕为空手道之王
to be crowned the king of karate
空手道岛
Karate Island?
我没听说过空手道岛
I've never heard of Karate Island
确实  珊迪
Sure, Sandy
空手道大师都会过去
all the big karate experts go there
可我空手道强得都能甩你好几条街了
But, my karate is better than yours by a country mile
岛那边从来没邀请过我
and I've never been invited
也许你空手道确实挺强
Maybe your karate was the best
不过现在那边认了个新的第一了
but now they've recognized a new number one
感觉有哪里不对劲
There's something rotten in the Alamo
最好还是跟你一起过去
I'd better tag along with you
看里面靠不靠谱
and see if it's on the up-and-up
好啊  珊迪
All right, Sandy
你可以随我前来目睹我的加冕时刻
you can come with me to witness my crowning moment
我们到了吗
Are we there yet?
到了
Yup
就在那边
That's it over there
你怎么会知道那是空手道岛
What make you think that's Karate Island?
欢迎来到空手道岛
不知道  刚好猜中了吧
I don't know, lucky guess?
你们好啊  空手道之王大驾光临
Hello there, the King of Karate has arrived
欢迎光临我的岛  海绵宝宝桑
Welcome to my island, SpongeBob-san
谢谢
Thank you
我是乌冬大师
I am Master Udon
你好  乌冬大师
Howdy, Master Udon
我是珊迪
Sandy Cheeks
我自己也会一点空手道
I do a little karate myself
珊迪珊迪珊迪
Sandy, Sandy, Sandy
乌冬大师对你这种空手道菜鸟没兴趣
Mr. Udon isn't interested in a karate novice like you
他只有加冕的时间
He only has time for royalty
真是的
Oh, brother
请你向我展示几招  海绵宝宝大师
Please, show me
some of your moves, Master SpongeBob
听见没  珊迪
You hear that, Sandy?
他叫我  大师
He called me "master"
你们最好的打手都放马过来
Bring on your best fighters
我尽量温和对待他们
I'll try to go easy on 'em
海绵宝宝  你空手道还不够强
SpongeBob, your karate's not good enough
打不过那几位硬茬
to handle those sidewinders
边看边学  小妹
Watch and learn, sister
对
Yup
空手道之王就这么强
That's how the King of Karate does it
下一个是谁
Who's next?
有点十分不对劲的味道
Something smells like rancid rodeo around here
厉害
Excellent
不愧是空手道之王
Truly, you are King of Karate
独一无二
The one and only
一定要做好准备为你举行加冕典礼
We must make ready for your coronation
我准备好成为空手道之王了
I'm ready to be King of Karate
空手道之王桑
King of Karate-san
你现在是时候
it is time for you
要坐上属于你的宝座了
to take your rightful place on your throne
我的宝座
My throne
好了  乌冬
All right, Udon
我盯着你呢
I'm on to you
这地方感觉有诈
This place is as crooked as a dizzy sidewinder
来吧  珊迪
Come, Sandy
在空手道之王旁边就座
take your place next to the king
分享我的巅峰时刻
and share in my crowning achievement
给我呼吸空气的朋友带个位子
Bring a seat for my air-breathing friend
海绵宝宝  你都滑头起来了
SpongeBob, y'all are getting a bit wily
我是不是察觉到了一丝妒忌呢  珊迪
Do I detect a note of jealousy, Sandy?
我能用空手道把你打得落花流水
Heck, I could karate you into a country fiddle
就算一只爪子绑背后也一样
with one paw tied behind my back
可是加冕为空手道之王的是谁呢
But who's being crowned King of Karate?
反正不是你
Not you
我不陪你闹了
I'm getting off this crazy train
大师  别理她了
Master, don't worry about her
她就快错过这千载难逢的好机会了
She is missing out on the opportunity of a lifetime
加冕仪式开始
Let the coronation begin
珊迪就快错过大好时机了
Sandy's going to miss out, big time
该死的海绵宝宝
That dang SpongeBob
他以为他谁啊
Who does he think he is?
那黄色自私鬼的格斗知识都是我教的
I taught that yellow egomaniac
everything he knows about fighting
而且还只是一点皮毛
and that ain't much
不要
No
海绵宝宝出事了
SpongeBob's in trouble
海绵宝宝可是空手道之王
SpongeBob is the "King of Karate"
根本就不需要我
He doesn't need me
他自己就能解决
He can handle this himself
珊迪
Sandy
我需要你
I need you
我自己没法解决
I can't handle this myself
坚持住  兄弟
Hold on, buddy
不要
No
珊迪
Sandy
她绝对没法救到你
She will never reach you
她必须先通过  四层恐惧
She must first pass through the "Four Floors of Fear"
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
要想过去  必须先打败我搔痒哥
You cannot pass unless you defeat me, The Tickler
还有我的铁指禅
and my iron-finger style
看
Look
准备迎接你的一生之痒吧
Prepare for the tickling of your life
尝尝这些
Taste these
不好
Oh no
果酱馅甜甜圈
Jelly-filled donuts?
你怎么知道那是我的弱点
How did you know they were my weakness?
果酱馅的吸引力无人能敌
No one can resist jelly-filled
黏在那别动  等会再回来给你上糖浆
Sticky around, I'll be back with the glazed
我需要湿巾
I could use a wet napkin
好了  下一个是谁
All right, who's next?
站住
Halt
没人可以通过我大嘴女这关
No one advances past me, Lipp Cervas
还有我的伸缩嘴唇冲刺术
and my power-flexi dynamo-lip thruster style
跳舞啊  小松鼠
Dance, squirrel, dance
进阶吹风机招
Advanced hair-dryer style
你用那玩意想干什么
What do you expect to do with that?
不好
Oh, no
嘴唇不能干
Not chapped lips
唇膏
你少废话了
That's enough lip out of you
嘴 唇
还没人能抵达肮脏菲尔的老巢
No one has ever made it to the lair of Filthy Phil
除了我没人能过关
No one passes except me
来感受我可怕体臭吧
Now, feel the steam of my horrible body odor
菲尔
Phil
你的恶臭可透不过我的新鲜空气罩
Your foul stench can't permeate my fresh-air dome
新鲜空气罩
Fresh-air dome?
我也太臭了
Man, I really do stink
你这位松鼠还挺强的
You are one impressive squirrel
连衣服都换了
You even made a costume change
放了海绵宝宝
Release SpongeBob
休想
Never
他要是想走  得先
He is forbidden to leave, until
签了这份合同
he signs this contract
合同
你在说什么鬼话
What are you talking about?
房地产
Real estate
你是说这一切
You mean this whole thing
都是骗我们买房地产设的套
was a scam to get us to buy real estate?
对
Yes
要是真有空手道岛的话
If there was a real Karate Island
我早就是有钱人了
I'd be a millionaire
你是说我不是空手道之王吗
You mean I'm not King of Karate?
没错
No
不过你可以当公寓之王
But you could be King of Condos
来  解释给你听
Here, let me explain
道理很简单
It's really quite simple
如果在公寓岛投资分时度假公寓
See, if you invest in a time share here on Condo Island
你资产就会增长十倍
you can see your equity increase ten-fold
你和你的黄色朋友
Perhaps you and your yellow friend
应该愿意投资分时度假公寓吧
would like to set up a timeshare plan?
千万别投资  珊迪
Don't do it, Sandy
我绝对不会中你的分时度假公寓圈套
I won't give in to your timeshare vacation scam
那就中我的拳头
Then give into my fists
这下你泡汤了吧  乌冬面
You're in the soup now, Udon
珊迪  对不起我刚在岛上特别欠
Sandy, I'm sorry I acted like a jerk back there
谢谢你解救我脱离
Thanks for saving me from
买公寓骗局
buying a condo
真是的  海绵宝宝
Aw, shucks, SpongeBob
朋友就该互挺
that's what friends are for
不过我还有个问题想问
I still have one question, though
这是不是说我再也不是空手道之王了
Does this mean I'm not King of Karate anymore?
在我看来你就是  海绵宝宝
You are in my book, SpongeBob
在我看来你就是
You are in my book
现在我来跟你讲解房地产
Now let me tell you about real estate
其关键在于选址
It's all about location
我来了
I'm here
竖笛之王大驾光临
The King of Clarinets has arrived